Well, I have a full day at the newspaper
office, so I've given you that list of
goods we need for Mrs.
Lawson's, and Jasper, please, just
what's on the list.
I'm trying to make sure that we don't
spend more than $2 this month, so it's
important that we just keep to our
budget.
All right, then.
Jasper, you haven't heard a word I've
said.
Oh, yes, uh, budget, yes, very tight.
Budget.
Mr. Harold B. Dunn, the man behind
Dunsburg, Pennsylvania, the city of the
future, is in Charlottetown.
Those that close to the entrepreneur say
that Mr. Dunn is looking for the site
of his next project.
Dunsville? Avonlea, it's become
Dunsville.
Now,
now, Rachel Lynn, you don't know what
the man's going to say.
You don't have to be a mind reader,
Archie Gillis. I couldn't agree with you
more, Rachel.
There's a first.
No Yankees going to come up here and buy
up all our property. Well, the next
thing you know, we'll have an invasion
of Americans, that's what. Can't you at
least give the man a fair hearing first
before manning the ramparts?
Are you telling me you're prepared to
entertain all this?
Come
right
in, Jasper.
Raleigh's Roll Oats is presenting this
display. It's a new sales venture, a
traveling motion picture show.
are so exciting.
Sorry.
Edison, protect...
How many frames? How many frames?
How many frames?
Look, I'm no Edison. I'm just here to
tell stereo.
Recreating real life like it actually
happens.
Oh,
moving pictures, such nonsense.
If you ask me, the world is changing too
fast for its own good. One day, moving
pictures, and Lord knows what next.
People on the moon, I suppose.
No doubt about that.
Oh, what?
Jasper, on the moon, really?
Well, why not? I mean, only a few
hundred years ago, people thought the
was flat.
Yes, well, I have some truly astonishing
news to announce.
All right. I feel it.
Angus McCorkadale has sold the cannery.
No. I don't believe it.
Oh, it's true.
And I heard directly from the horse's
mouth.
Rachel Lynn.
That the buyer is that Yankee
millionaire, H .B. Dunn. Dunn, that's
that just built Dunsburg, the city of
the future.
Oh, it was all over the Charlottetown
paper this morning.
Scientific claptrap, that's what it is.
He buys up land on which he builds
modern homes and stores, and then his
company leases them back to the town's
population.
And that's supposed to be sound, is it?
Well, the king's farm could be next
door.
Why not the entire community, for that
matter?
Can't stop progress, Hedy.
Progress, you call it?
You and your progress, Jasper.
Why, your scientific tinkering don't
bring your two dimes so rough together.
Eddie King.
Well, if you weren't so enamored with
all this moving picture nonsense, you'd
notice you have a family to support.
Our family is supported just fine,
Eddie.
I'll get some milk, Angelivia.
Oh, yes, well, I suppose financial
difficulties are none of my affair.
But wise, Jasper. You would have taken
my advice in the first place and gone
found a proper job.
That's one of the things.
Oh, yes, that was a very sound idea.
I think that I've been spending too much
time in my workshop.
Jasper.
Well, let's not discuss it now, anyway.
I know, I know.
I'm going to put aside my experimental
workshop for a while.
Well, I won't let you even think of
working in a bank.
No, no, no. I'm going to do some serious
writing.
I shall see about getting articles
published, because I haven't been doing
fair share of looking after the
expenses.
Jasper, that's not even true, you see.
Now you're just letting Hetty's opinions
rankle you. No, no.
Mine's made up.
Less time on tinkering, more time on
financial responsibilities.
Uncle
Jasper?
Hmm?
Do you really think that everyone in
Avonlea will let Mr. Dunbar up the town?
Oh. Well, I don't exactly know. These
company towns, they're becoming very
popular down in the States.
I'm just worried that this town will
change somehow.
Progress can't be stopped.
The past is never the same.
The future.
What's all this?
Oh, sounds foolish, but this is a letter
that I'm writing to the...
Thomas Edison Company in New Jersey to
tell of my theories. You know, the one
about the motion picture?
And Mr. Edison is a scientist and a
filmmaker, so he'll understand.
Theory?
I've been doing quite a bit of thinking
lately.
You see, it depends on the number of
frames and the speed at which they're
shown to convey the action. And I
thought perhaps with 22 or 24 frames...
Instead of the usual 18, which the
Edison projectors
project at now, that it would complete
the action.
See, the additional four or six frames
would smooth out the action.
That's wonderful.
Why don't you build your own new
improved camera?
I can't.
I was going to try to, but...
Rather short of funds.
Truth be told, it's not been a very good
year, financially.
What with Montgomery and all, and... Me
need to buckle down, like your aunt
Eddie said. I need to publish
more articles.
Secretly.
I thought, what if the Edison people
were to hire me to do the experiments?
Uncle Jasper, you have to do that.
You absolutely must.
It's a brilliant idea, and I'm sure
they'd hire you.
Besides, I mean, publishing articles is
all well and good, but you have to go on
inventing. I don't want you to change.
Well, thank you, Sarah. That makes two.
You and Olivia.
I'll mail that for you if you like.
Oh, thank you. You're very kind.
No,
thank you.
I am anxious to get going on the article
for the
Royal Society of Naturalists who have
promised to pay me a small sum
for my troubles.
Bye, Uncle Jasper.
Um, yeah.
Bye.
Aunt Hattie, I need to speak with you
frankly right away.
Oh, be frank by all means, but kindly
wipe off your boots. I've just polished
the floor.
I've come to a very important decision.
I think that with all the weight of my
affairs on your shoulders, I should have
more of a say in the way my trust is
being administered.
I'd like to make a very small investment
in something I believe strongly about.
Well, that's good.
I've selected an investment.
Would you like some advice in that area?
After all, it is a very tricky
business. You want to choose wisely.
I'd like to invest in the arts.
You don't mean silly things like plays
and actors, do you? That's a sure way to
fritter away your money.
But you used to always lecture to us in
the classroom about how Queen Elizabeth
supported Shakespeare in the 16th
century.
You yourself have made your fortune by
being a writer.
That's true.
Aunt Hetty, this is my destiny.
To help the people that I want to
because I can afford to.
Tell you what.
Let's draft a letter.
You and I.
Come on.
To your solicitors in Montreal.
They're sure to come up with a sound
suggestion.
Aunt Hetty, my father left this for me
to deal with ultimately.
And I honestly feel that I am old enough
to...
To know how to invest a small amount of
my money, wisely and on my own.
Yes, but, child, people might take
advantage of your kind nature.
That's why all requests for money from
the trustees must come through me
directly. But... Can't be too careful.
The only truly safe place for your
fortune is in property or in the bank.
And take it from me, the Queen of
England owns them both.
Now...
To your solicitors.
Quiet!
Quiet, please!
May I have your attention?
As you know, this is an open meeting to
discuss the proposed intentions of the
American, Mr.
Harold Dunn.
Mr. Dunn, you may take the stand.
I understand you're all anxious to know
what my plans are for the cannery.
My proposition to your lovely hamlet of
Avonlea is to transform it into
Dunsville.
The city of the future.
The new and expanded cannery will
operate with the working precepts
late by Mr. Henry Ford of the state of
Michigan.
As with Dunsburg, Pennsylvania, we have
already shown that such a city plan...
built to support an expanded cannery and
other proposed automated factory plants
in the area will work and is
overwhelmingly beneficial to the local
How beneficial?
Beneficial for whom exactly, Mr. Dunn? I
want to know what's going to happen to
me and mine, sir.
My family depends on the cannery for
three square meals on the table.
I am a family man myself, sir, and there
is nothing more important to me than
the welfare of my loved ones, giving
them a decent place to live, providing
them. That means clothes on their backs
and food on their table.
That is a new harbor for larger vessels
and a railroad to transport goods and
people. Dunsville means prosperity.
That's what my city of the future is all
about.
It means affordable homes with running
water and electricity, telephones and
indoor plumbing, bringing the farming
communities, every community, into the
20th century.
Bert, did you hear that?
Indoor necessities.
I hear a lot of talk, Clara.
Can you imagine, Bert? Let's get indoor
plumbing for our new home.
What new home?
The one we're buying when we sell the
old one to Mr. Dunn. I'm not selling,
I'm not buying anything.
An outhouse is good enough for a pot.
Let's try and keep our heads, everyone.
After all, nobody gives away something
for nothing.
Good point.
What's the catch, Mr. Dunn?
No catch, sir.
Certain properties will be needed to
realize our goal.
May I ask just why you picked Avonlea?
Honestly, madam, the Nova Scotia
properties were too expensive.
So you think our land can be acquired
more cheaply, is that it?
This man will control the very life of
the town.
Well, you'll be renting your property
back from him, shopping in his stores,
buying everything from him.
He'll run you out of business, Elvira.
You too, Archie Gillis.
Well, what... What properties are we
talking about, Mr. Dunn?
Take a good look at the plans here,
depicting the high standard of daily
that can be yours in the city of the
future.
Now, I know that you will all need time
to think about my proposal, and I am
only too happy to leave offers with you
and return in a month's time for your
decision. The brochure will give you all
the details of the plans.
Please, come closer.
Good Lord.
What is that contraption plunk in the
middle of my yard? That's company
headquarters. Well, according to this
plan, that runs right through the middle
of my home, Mr. Dunn. Well, we are not
without alternatives, but you will be
adequately compensated and a new modern
home can be yours at the right price.
What's those buildings there? The main
storage facilities.
That's Green Gables.
You're not going along with that, Mr.
Harrison.
Merle, a cutthroat, would roll over in
her grave.
I'd say yes if I were you, Harrison.
It'd be a sweet deal for you.
Oh, there are people who cannot be
bought, Archie Gillis. And I ain't one
them. Well, I can tell you right now
that I'm ready to sell, Mr. Dunn.
Need the money.
How much?
Cash in the barrel.
You paint a rosy picture of this
Dunsville.
But I'm quite sure that the reality
won't bear much resemblance to the
Where are the people in it? Where are
the open spaces, the orchards and
wildflowers, the rows of farmer's
fields? Miss King, my ideas may not be
everyone's cup of tea, but believe me,
they are for the good of the majority.
Oh, they're not for my good.
Well, all I've got so far is just a lot
of hot air from Angus McCorky about the
sale of the cannery. How much does that
cost you?
Sir,
I'm a woman of independent means, and
I'm prepared to compensate you for your
trouble so far. That is, buy it back.
Well, if you won't accept my offer, then
I'll...
Then I'll get an injunction from the
crown and I'll investigate you and this
-called city of the future.
Oh, I have the funds, Mr. Dunn, believe
you me.
I have the funds.
The king seems mighty eager to spend
some money.
Plenty of royalties, my wager.
She'll need more than that to equal what
Mr. Dunn is paying out.
I wonder how many people would sell to
Hattie King if she offered more money.
Two bidders make for a better price.
You can't mean it, you layly bugle. Oh!
Here's where Rose Cottage butts up
against the Campbell property, which we
know, and here is the King firm, and
right here.
It's the piece of land that Mr. Dunn is
after for his railroad throughway.
Is that all? Just that little square?
Janet, if you had anything substantial
between your ears, you'd understand that
that little square, as you call it, is
crucial.
Without that little square, Mr.
Dunn would have to change the entire
direction of the railroad, which would
him a fortune.
Oh, well, then why don't we charge him a
fortune and sell him our little square?
Janet, we don't want to sell our little
square.
Why ever not? It's just a little tiny
piece of land.
I think that's a good point. It's just a
small bit of family property.
What do you think, Jasper?
Well, I think progress always entails a
certain amount of controversy.
Actually, I don't think that it's my
place to... No, thank the Lord it's not
your place, and I'll thank you, Jasper
Dale, to keep your ideas to yourself.
Harry, I asked Jasper for his opinion.
I don't care about Jasper's opinion.
Fine, then.
Why, here's my opinion. I think we
should sell.
Olivia!
Take and leave of your senses?
What harm could it possibly do? At least
we'd be making some kind of a
contribution to a more progressive
community.
Don't you see what you're agreeing to?
A railroad?
Running across our land?
The noise, the smell, the commotion?
I would only run once a day.
Janet, I must insist that you leave this
to Hetty and Olivia and me.
Oh, you insist.
You insist.
I'm your wife, and my opinion means
nothing.
I think you've both got blinkers on. You
can't stand in the way of progress.
Olivia, I am deeply shocked at this
betrayal.
And I can't help but feel that if your
husband had done the right thing when
Montgomery was born, you'd not be so
desperate now to get out of our
straits herein.
You don't know anything about our
financial straits, and I'll thank you to
your opinions to yourself.
We're leaving.
Yes, I'm leaving too.
Janet, Olivia, simmer down.
No, you simmer down.
Why can't you two control your emotions?
Just stack the tea things there, will
you, dear?
Very silent.
Suppose you have an opinion too, do you?
My opinion?
I think you're making life miserable for
both Aunt Olivia and Uncle Jasper.
The way you attack him is absolutely
insulting. He's her own husband.
Sarah, I... And besides... If you're
constantly asking people to think for
themselves, don't be surprised if they
don't always agree with you.
Felix, the White Sands Hotel is the only
telephone line I can actively use to
make a private telephone call.
I couldn't use the one at the general
store. Everyone would hear.
Felix, you have to help me.
Why does it have to be so private?
I thought Sarah or I won't help you.
Look, I went ahead and I ordered a
motion picture camera for Uncle Jasper
the Thomas Edison Company in New Jersey.
Really? How'd you ever get Aunt Hedy to
pay for it?
Well, I'm going to ask for the money
from my trustees whether Aunt Hedy
with it or not.
I know I'm going to get in trouble.
In here, there's a private telephone for
the guests.
You'll have to get the operator.
Have you got the number? Of course.
Stand watch.
Yes, I'd like the Montreal operator,
please.
Yes, this is Miss Hette King.
K -I -N -G.
I'm telephoning my solicitor, Mr. Edward
Bartholomew of Bartholomew of Finlay
and Howe.
Here we are, your lady.
It's Hetty King's latest effort.
Where there's a will, there's a way.
It's all about a miserable old woman and
her rich niece.
Wonder where she got that idea.
Let me see it. I just loved her last
novel. We sold out all our copies.
The Curse of the Spinster's Fortune.
Really, Elvira.
I'll get that telephone.
Oh, no, you, Lily, it's not for us. One
ring means someone's using it over at
the White Sands.
Speaking of fortunes...
What did you make of Hetty King's trying
to vie with Mr. Dunn's offer?
Really? Hetty? What did she say?
She said she'd buy him out. That's what.
Oh, Jasmine, it's all a lot of bluster.
Hetty King, even with all her royalties,
doesn't own that kind of money.
No, but her niece does.
Sarah Stanley.
She's got bushel baskets full of it.
Oh, um, would you let me borrow that
book after you're done with it, Rachel?
Think of it.
Let me have another look at a pivotal
section here right near the end
where the old woman steals the fortune
of the young girl.
Oh, no, Eulalie. Hang up. It's the White
Sands again.
You speak to Mr.
Bartholomew. I have an urgent business
matter that requires... Immediate
attention.
The funds will be wired right away.
Good.
Right you are.
Good Lord.
Hang up, you lady.
It's a sin to listen in on someone
else's call.
You won't believe what I just heard.
You're pale as a ghost, you lady bugle.
It was Hattie King ordering up funds
from Sarah's trust.
An urgent business matter, she said.
You know how life imitates art?
She just did it.
Are you sure it was Hetty?
I ought to know that voice, Elvira
Lawson.
I'm telling you, Hetty King is going to
use those funds to buy up this town and
sell it back to Mr. Dunn. No two ways
about it.
Who would have thought it possible?
Judas, in our very midst.
The funds will be wired to the Thomas
Edison Company, New Jersey, on behalf of
an order in the name of Jasper Dale.
Thank you kindly, my good man.
Oh, hello, Sarah.
The postmaster asked me to deliver this
to you.
Seems to be from the Edison Company.
Very, very kind of you.
Kind of you.
Dale received your letter.
You proposed theories to our attention.
Free?
Motion picture camera, Jasper, that's
impossible.
Absolutely. No, the letter says they
received my correspondence about the
and, quote, they say, it is your
scientific obligation to conduct these
experiments to improve any frailties in
our original camera invention.
Unquote.
Jasper, that's wonderful.
Lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky, lucky day.
Imagine an Edison omnibus portable
picture camera.
It'll take a bit of time, won't it?
I'll have to test it and change the
camera. Oh, Jasper, now don't you worry
about our own problems.
This is the opportunity of a lifetime.
You've got to do it.
I'll manage financially. We'll be fine.
Yes.
Too good to be true.
All right.
Sarah, could you get Montgomery's
nappies for me?
What's the matter? Have you had enough
of that?
An Edison omnibus motion picture camera.
An Edison omnibus motion picture
camera.
I used to love that lullaby when you
were a baby, Sarah.
Your mother used to sing it to you all
the time.
She did.
I can't remember.
I know I was only three when she died,
but sometimes I lay awake at night and I
try to remember the sound of her voice.
If only I could just hear it in my head.
It frightens me sometimes.
There are pictures, but... I can't
really remember what she looked like.
Well, there she looked just like you.
You won't think I'm silly if I tell you
something?
No, tell me.
Sometimes... I just wish I could see her
just one more time.
Just... Just hear the sound of her
voice.
And see her face.
There's so much I always wanted to know
about her.
He's working for the Thomas Edison
Company.
He's perfecting an invention for them.
doing motion photography experiments.
Out of my way!
Jasper, get out of the road.
Just need a minute, just need a minute.
Well, I haven't got all day to wait for
you and your infernal invention.
I'm working for the Thomas Edison
Company.
Jasper working?
Not really my invention.
They've asked me to experiment on one of
theirs. Well, that's all well and good,
but I've got a business to run. Now I
want you and it out of the way. If we
could hear if he calls me, please.
The road is yours.
Take them, Mr. Dunne, and you can shove
them down your parchment water faucet.
What do you want? There it is.
Get that contraction out of my face,
Jasper Dale.
Move the arm. Move the arm more.
I'll move the arm for you in a minute,
I'll tell you.
Good.
What do you think you're doing?
Motion picture, Eddie.
Motion picture?
Experiments in motion, hence the laundry
for the Edison Company, New Jersey.
You mean to say that somebody has hired
you to make a moving
picture? Not hired, exactly.
Conducting research.
I see. So you're making a moving picture
of my...
Laundry line and for nothing.
It's the motion that I'm interested in.
Oh, Jasper, dear.
Are you duck -raving mad?
Just keep doing what you're doing. I
won't be in the way.
Oh, you most certainly will not. Have
you stopped?
What's the matter?
Don't just stand there. Help me.
May I have escaped your notice, Jasper?
Was it you?
Once you waste your time tinkering with
that toy, some of us are trying to
preserve our homes and our farms and our
very way of life.
Thank you, dear.
I will not have my foundation garments
in a motion picture.
Not for Thomas Edison, nor anyone else
for that matter.
So just be gone with her. Gone.
Don't let me catch you skulking around
here with that thing.
Gone.
dying. I don't care if it's for the
Queen of Sheba.
I'd not let her peruse my laundry
either.
Don't look at me, my boy, just act
naturally.
I want to see your arm moving back and
forward.
Would Miss King please clear the
picture?
Oh, Jeff, for goodness sakes, shut off
that ridiculous contraption.
Don't!
Stop it!
Well, Ed, you're pestering the entire
community.
He isn't bothering anyone, Aunt Hattie.
Well, he's bothering me.
Let go, Clara!
Clear!
Clear! How can you begrudge me one small
convenience?
We are not living in a Dunsville home,
so we are not needing a Dunsville
contraction.
Come on, Bert.
What's wrong with a new home?
Stay out of this, Archie.
from that infernal contraction, aren't
you, Gillis? You are responsible for
this, Bert. Don't blame Bert Potts.
Blame Hattie King.
She's the one that's responsible for
this whole town going berserk. I beg
pardon? She's in cahoots with that
despicable Mr.
Dunn. She's stealing money from Sarah's
funds to help Mr.
Dunn buy up Avonlea.
You lilly -biggle, that is a bald -faced
lie.
Why ever would you dream up such errant
nonsense?
All here in your latest novel. The rich
niece, the forgery.
Deny that if you can, Hattie King.
Don't be ridiculous. It's a novel.
A novel. I made it up.
You didn't make up that telephone call I
heard.
What telephone call?
I know what I heard.
Oh, Wager, somebody ought to get a
constable. I listened in on the line,
heard you tell Sarah's solicitors that
you needed to borrow money from her
trust.
Excuse me, but Hedy King is as honest as
the day is long.
Oh, thank you, Jasper. Aunt Hedy, listen
to me.
It's my fault.
I made that telephone call, and I
pretended to be you.
I imitated your voice.
I just needed to get the money for that
motion picture camera for Jasper.
I just thought he should be able to do
what he wanted, and I wanted you and
Olivia to stop arguing.
Am I?
No, this isn't.
Fine kettle of fish.
You won't get away with this, heavy
king.
Now, listen here, you layly bugle.
That's quite enough of that.
If you must know, Sarah herself did the
damage.
She just told me so, and I'm... Oh, I am
shocked and appalled.
Just as she imitated my voice and
wheedled funds from her solicitor so she
buy that brother -in -law of mine a
camera of all things.
Working for Thomas Edison, my auntie.
Hey, a good money for one of Jasper
Dale's inventions.
Uncle Jasper, I'm sorry.
I thought it would be better for
everyone if you two stopped arguing over
Jasper. See now what your planks and
schemes have brought you to.
Oh, and not just you, my girl.
Why, the humiliation to have had my
character impugned and maligned by that
eulalie bugle of all people.
Jasper Dale running amok there with his
silly hammer.
You enjoy fighting.
I think Uncle Jasper's clever. He's very
clever. And he should be able to
experiment and try out all of his new
wonderful ideas.
He should be able to make important
discoveries.
Aunt Hattie, he deserves our support
because we can afford to give it to him.
support?
That'll be the day.
Now, you listen to me, Sarah Stanley.
If you ever converse with your
solicitors again, ever, without my
shall...
Well, I'm not sure what I'll do, but
it'll be dramatic.
Well, I'll tell you what I'll do.
If you don't stop picking on Jasper,
I'll leave you and I'll go back to
and I'll live with Danny Louisa.
You have a kind heart, child. I know
that.
It's just the machinations of your
brains I worry about.
I'm sorry. I know I'm too wound up about
this. It's just I'm afraid.
Afraid for all of us.
Oh, Evan, they can't change it, mustn't
they?
I won't let it.
May I come in?
Well, I'm not stopping you, Emma.
Did Jasper return the cameras I told him
to?
Oh, Eddie, Jasper is so despondent.
He spent so much time and energy and he
is so close to a breakthrough on
improving that camera.
Won't you let him keep it just to finish
his work?
Perhaps I don't understand.
I take it you refuse to help save our
land from Mr. Dunn, and yet you want me
now to help out Jasper. Why on earth
would I say yes to that request?
Eddie, I didn't mean to go against
family wishes. I was only being contrary
oppose you.
I was trying to defend Jasper.
Oh, Eddie, you just don't understand.
Jasper... is devastated.
And you know he really believes all
those awful things you have said about
Aunt Hetty, you can't force him to take
back that camera.
It's my money and I want him to keep it.
If you don't apologize immediately, I'm
packing my bags for Montreal.
And Mr. Edison wasn't really interested
in my theory.
What a fool I was for thinking that he
might be.
And after this, everyone is now
convinced that your father is a
crackpot.
Maybe I am.
But I wanted to do this for you ever so
much, my son.
And as I was making these pictures all
through the town, I knew that I could
make a real motion picture.
Before it's all lost.
A real recording. Something to remember
us by.
The way we looked.
The way we laughed.
The way the whole town lived.
I want very badly to give that to you.
Something that you could show your son.
One day.
Something that your children would
treasure.
Sometime when we're dead.
I've let you down, miss.
Eddie.
Olivia's not here.
Yes, well, I... I'm not here to see
Olivia. I'm here to speak
with you, Jasper. I know what you're
going to say.
I've already packed it up straight there
under your nose.
Jasper Dale, I... I realise we are not
all cut out of the same cloth.
No, you are who you are and will do what
you do, and that's that.
But maybe you and your newfangled
motion picture, maybe just the thing to
save my Avonlea from the
dreaded Dunsville.
You lost me.
We're going to finish your darn moving
pictures.
And we'll show them to you at the next
town meeting.
Say a change is inevitable.
Well, then, let's change their mind.
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for
returning this evening in such large
numbers. I am pleased to know that so
many of you wish to see the world as I
heading into a bright future.
Make no mistake.
What I offer you will raise the standard
of living of every man, woman, and
child.
My associates here will circulate
amongst the crowd to collect the signed
by all vendors.
Oh, most eloquent, Mr. Dunn, but first,
perhaps you'll let us state our
case.
But of course.
It would be a pleasure. The floor is
yours, Miss King.
What
is
this? Oh, just an experiment.
This is Avonlea.
This is the Avonlea I know, with all its
many inhabitants, of whom I'm history
proud to say I'm one.
We are farmers, true.
One and all, we come from noble, hearty
stock, Scottish, English, and Irish.
We are proud and God -fearing.
Too, I believe that good fortune has
shone on us, making this island our very
happy home.
And you may be sure that life here isn't
all work and no play.
likes its drama.
And we do it, too, with plenty of zip
and enthusiasm.
I like to think of us as one large
family, and like true family members,
we don't always get along.
We do care a great deal for one another,
and one day when we grow old and
bid adieu to this fair earth wonder,
hope there'll be others to take our
and feel as passionately about Avonlea
as we do.
Why, someday the images you see may be
all that's left of the town we love so
dearly.
than I was supposed to be.
Little left to tell of our simple
existence.
But then perhaps this moving picture
will speak to those who come after of
we P .E. Islanders grew up, lived,
married, and died here at the beginning
of the 20th century.
Which is why we have chosen this way to
record for all time our response
to... Mr. Dunn's offer to buy up our
town.
So, when you look around you at the
haunted hill,
at the homestead lights, at the fields
tilled by the dead and gone who love
you will say...
Why, I've come home.
Life.
We're lucky enough to live each moment
of every day and... Jasper Dale has been
fortuitous and ingenious enough to
capture that we and future
generations... We know it.
Thank you, Miss King. If that is the end
of your presentation, then my
associates will now pick up the signed
offers.
Cash on the barrelhead.